<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project>
    <people>
        <group>
            <title>Project Team</title>
            <members>
                <person>
                    <title>Dr.</title>
                    <name>Noah Millstone</name>
                    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
                    <institution>University of Birmingham</institution>
                    <bio>Mauris eget fermentum neque. Duis vehicula eleifend nunc sed malesuada.
                        Ut scelerisque pharetra eros ut porttitor. Nulla sit amet placerat lectus, 
                        ut varius erat. Interdum et malesuada fames ac ante ipsum primis in 
                        faucibus. Quisque tristique nunc luctus commodo interdum. Suspendisse 
                        nisi justo, rutrum sed dolor vitae, tempor rutrum enim.</bio>
                </person>
                <person>
                    <title>Dr.</title>
                    <name>Sebastiaan Verweij</name>
                    <role>Co-Investigator</role>
                    <institution>University of Bristol</institution>
                    <bio>Sebastiaan Verweij is Lecturer in Late Medieval and Early Modern Literature 
                        at the Department of English at the University of Bristol. He was previously 
                        a researcher for <em>Scriptorium: Medieval and Early Modern Manuscripts Online</em>, 
                        and <em>The Oxford Edition of the Sermons of John Donne</em>. His first book 
                        <em>The Literary Culture of Early Modern Scotland: Manuscript Production and 
                            Transmission, 1560-1625</em> (Oxford University Press, 2016) has won 
                            the Saltire Society's 'Scottish Research Book of the Year 2016' award. 
                            He is also currently at work, with Professor Peter McCullough, on the 
                            <em>Textual Companion</em> volume in <em>The Oxford Edition of the Sermons 
                            of John Donne</em>. See further info see 
                            <a href="http://research-information.bristol.ac.uk/person/s.verweij">http://research-information.bristol.ac.uk/person/s.verweij</a>.</bio>
                </person>
                <person>
                    <title>Mr.</title>
                    <name>Richard Bell</name>
                    <role>Research Associate</role>
                    <institution>University of Birmingham</institution>
                    <bio>Mauris eget fermentum neque. Duis vehicula eleifend nunc sed malesuada.
                        Ut scelerisque pharetra eros ut porttitor. Nulla sit amet placerat lectus, 
                        ut varius erat. Interdum et malesuada fames ac ante ipsum primis in 
                        faucibus. Quisque tristique nunc luctus commodo interdum. Suspendisse 
                        nisi justo, rutrum sed dolor vitae, tempor rutrum enim.</bio>
                </person>
                <person>
                    <title>Mr.</title>
                    <name>Mike Jones</name>
                    <role>Developer</role>
                    <institution>University of Bristol</institution>
                    <bio>Mike Jones has over eighteen years’ experience of software development, 
                        working with numerous software languages, frameworks, open standards and 
                        metadata standards. He has expertise and knowledge of Python and Java 
                        development, XML technologies, and web and mobile development. Since 
                        joining the University of Bristol in 2006 Mike has worked on a large 
                        number of externally funded projects, including the AHRC-funded 
                        <a href="http://knowyourbristol.org/">Know Your Bristol On the Move</a> and 
                        <a href="http://outstories.knowyourbristol.org/">Outstories</a> projects</bio>
                </person>
            </members>
        </group>
    </people>
</project>
