<?xml version="1.0"?>
<project xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
    <abbr>MPESE</abbr>
    <title>Manuscript Pamphleteering in Early Stuart England</title>
    <abstract>
        <em>Manuscript Pamphleteering in Early Stuart England</em> is an AHRC-funded project that
        will map a large but little-known corpus of handwritten political pamphlets that were
        composed in England between the Stuart accession (1603) and the outbreak of Civil War
        (1642).</abstract>
    <description>
        <p>Before the outbreak of Civil War in 1642, England developed a large, influential and
            often radical pamphlet literature. Speeches, learned briefs, and scaffold apologies
            joined character assassinations, secret histories and conspiracy theories in a jumbled
            literary underground. Pamphlets were produced commercially and informally and circulated
            across the kingdom; they fascinated readers and influenced events. Large numbers of
            copies survive - probably in the tens of thousands - suggesting a significant
            readership. Nevertheless, this pamphlet literature is rarely mentioned and even more
            rarely analyzed by historians or literary critics, not least because it was written by
            hand rather than printed with movable type.</p>
        <p>This project aims to survey the vast hidden archive of early Stuart England's manuscript
            pamphlets. In collaboration with the British Library, this project will construct a
            database of manuscript pamphlet texts, bibliographic information, and digital images.
            This will allow users to search transcriptions of the pamphlets; analyze the
            distribution of copies through time and space; and see how such materials were
            presented: large and small, elaborate and plain, professional and amateur. The project
            will conduct additional research in the private papers of Francis Russell, fourth earl
            of Bedford, who was a major political figure of the early Stuart era as well as a reader
            and collector of manuscript pamphlets.</p>
        <p>The research has three main purposes. First, the project team and associated researchers
            will use the database to ask and answer fundamental questions about the content of early
            Stuart political ideas, the genres in which they were expressed, and the circulation of
            those ideas through the kingdom. Second, the studies produced by the project and the
            underlying dataset will be useful to historians, literary critics and scholars of
            political thought, providing a major new set of sources and a useful new set of research
            tools. Third, the project will prove useful to non-academic beneficiaries. Events at
            local archives, undertaken with the advice of the British Library, will raise the
            profile of the resource, and assist such archives and their users in capitalizing on
            manuscript pamphlets within their own collection; further, working in partnership with
            the Historical Association, the project will convene a Bristol-based group of secondary
            school teachers to help build a teaching resource for use in A-Level teaching, which
            will be available on the website and promoted by the Historical Association.</p>
    </description>
    <image>
        <url>resources/img/083404_snippet.png</url>
        <description>Folger Shakespeare Library, V.b.234.</description>
        <copyright>Folger Shakespeare Library under a CC BY-SA 4.0 license.</copyright>
    </image>
    <people>
        <group id="project_team">
            <title>Project Team</title>
            <members>
                <person>
                    <name>Noah Millstone</name>
                    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
                    <institution>University of Birmingham</institution>
                    <bio>Noah Millstone is a Birmingham Fellow in the Department of History at the
                        University of Birmingham. Prior to coming to Birmingham, Millstone received
                        a Ph.D. from Stanford University, held a Prize Fellowship in Economics,
                        History and Politics at Harvard University, and was a lecturer in history at
                        the University of Bristol. His first book, <em>Manuscript Circulation and
                            the Invention of Politics in Early Stuart England</em>, was published in
                        2016.</bio>
                </person>
                <person>
                    <name>Sebastiaan Verweij</name>
                    <role>Co-Investigator</role>
                    <institution>University of Bristol</institution>
                    <bio>Sebastiaan Verweij is Lecturer in Late Medieval and Early Modern Literature
                        at the Department of English at the University of Bristol. He was previously
                        a researcher for <em>Scriptorium: Medieval and Early Modern Manuscripts
                            Online</em>, and <em>The Oxford Edition of the Sermons of John
                            Donne</em>. His first book <em>The Literary Culture of Early Modern
                            Scotland: Manuscript Production and Transmission, 1560-1625</em> (Oxford
                        University Press, 2016) has won the Saltire Society's 'Scottish Research
                        Book of the Year 2016' award. He is also currently at work, with Professor
                        Peter McCullough, on the <em>Textual Companion</em> volume in <em>The Oxford
                            Edition of the Sermons of John Donne</em>. For further info see <a
                            href="http://research-information.bristol.ac.uk/person/s.verweij"
                            >http://research-information.bristol.ac.uk/person/s.verweij</a>.</bio>
                </person>
                <person>
                    <name>Richard Bell</name>
                    <role>Research Associate</role>
                    <institution>University of Birmingham</institution>
                    <bio>Richard Bell is a Research Associate in the Department of History at the
                        University of Birmingham. He recently completed his Ph.D. at Stanford
                        University on the politics of imprisonment for debt in seventeenth-century
                        London and was a 2016-17 Scouloudi Fellow at the Institute of Historical
                        Research in London.</bio>
                </person>
                <person>
                    <name>Mike Jones</name>
                    <role>Developer</role>
                    <institution>University of Bristol</institution>
                    <bio>Mike Jones has over eighteen years’ experience of software development,
                        working with numerous software languages, frameworks, open standards and
                        metadata standards. He has expertise and knowledge of Python and Java
                        development, XML technologies, and web and mobile development. Since joining
                        the University of Bristol in 2006 Mike has worked on a large number of
                        externally funded projects, including the AHRC-funded <a
                            href="http://knowyourbristol.org/">Know Your Bristol On the Move</a> and
                            <a href="http://outstories.knowyourbristol.org/">Outstories</a>
                        projects</bio>
                </person>
                <person>
                    <name>Jon Hallett</name>
                    <role>Systems Administrator</role>
                    <institution>University of Bristol</institution>
                    <bio>Jon Hallett is the systems administrator for the Research IT team at the University of Bristol. 
                    He has worked in university IT for over twenty years and in that time has administered the full stack of technologies 
                    in use in higher education, from patch cables to departmental IT infrastructure to critical corporate systems. His 
                    skills include Puppet, Python, Perl, Unix, databases and networking.</bio>
                </person>
            </members>
        </group>
        <group id="committee">
            <title>Senior Advisory Committee</title>
            <members>
                <person>
                    <name>Richard Cust</name>
                    <institution>University of Birmingham</institution>
                </person>
                <person>
                    <name>Jason Peacey</name>
                    <institution>University College London</institution>
                </person>
                <person>
                    <name>Andrew McRae</name>
                    <institution>University of Exeter</institution>
                </person>
                <person>
                    <name>Alexandra Walsham</name>
                    <institution>University of Cambridge</institution>
                </person>
            </members>
        </group>
        <group id="board">
            <title>Advisory Board</title>
            <members>
                <person>
                    <name>Hugh Adlington</name>
                    <institution>University of Birmingham</institution>
                </person>
                <person>
                    <name>Alastair Bellany</name>
                    <institution>Rutgers University</institution>
                </person>
                <person>
                    <name>Lloyd Bowen</name>
                    <institution>Cardiff University</institution>
                </person>
                <person>
                    <name>Christopher Burlinson</name>
                    <institution>Jesus College, Cambridge</institution>
                </person>
                <person>
                    <name>David Coast</name>
                    <institution>Bath Spa University</institution>
                </person>
                <person>
                    <name>Thomas Cogswell</name>
                    <institution>University of California Riverside</institution>
                </person>
                <person>
                    <name>David Como</name>
                    <institution>Stanford University)</institution>
                </person>
                <person>
                    <name>Paul Dingman</name>
                    <institution>Folger Shakespeare Library</institution>
                </person>
                <person>
                    <name>Joshua Eckhardt</name>
                    <institution>Virginia Commonwealth University</institution>
                </person>
                <person>
                    <name>Ann Hughes</name>
                    <institution>Emeritus, Keele University</institution>
                </person>
                <person>
                    <name>Jonathan Gibson</name>
                    <institution>Open University</institution>
                </person>
                <person>
                    <name>Chris Kyle</name>
                    <institution>Syracuse University</institution>
                </person>
                <person>
                    <name>Peter Lake</name>
                    <institution>Vanderbilt University</institution>
                </person>
                <person>
                    <name>Arthur F. Marotti</name>
                    <institution>Emeritus, Wayne State University</institution>
                </person>
                <person>
                    <name>Steven W. May</name>
                    <institution>Adjunct Professor, Emory University</institution>
                </person>
                <person>
                    <name>Julia Merritt</name>
                    <institution>University of Nottingham</institution>
                </person>
                <person>
                    <name>Anthony Milton</name>
                    <institution>University of Sheffield</institution>
                </person>
                <person>
                    <name>Rupali Mishra</name>
                    <institution>Auburn University</institution>
                </person>
                <person>
                    <name>Michael Questier</name>
                    <institution>Queen Mary University</institution>
                </person>
                <person>
                    <name>Daniel Starza-Smith</name>
                    <institution>King's College London</institution>
                </person>
                <person>
                    <name>Laura Stewart</name>
                    <institution>University of York</institution>
                </person>
                <person>
                    <name>Angus Vine</name>
                    <institution>University of Stirling</institution>
                </person>
                <person>
                    <name>Alison Wiggins</name>
                    <institution>University of Glasgow</institution>
                </person>
                <person>
                    <name>Heather Wolfe</name>
                    <institution>Folger Shakespeare Library</institution>
                </person>
                <person>
                    <name>Henry Woudhuysen</name>
                    <institution>Lincoln College, Oxford</institution>
                </person>
            </members>
        </group>
    </people>
</project>
